Three, two, one.
Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer. Well, we open up with the
ten commandments that God had written
for the whole world to keep. Brother
James. Yes, sir. And God spake all these
words, saying, I am the Lord thy God,
which have brought thee out of the land
of Egypt, out of the house of bondage.
Thou shalt have no other gods before me.
Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above, or that is in the
earth beneath, or that is in the water
under the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God, am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain, for the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Sixth day shalt thou labor
and do all thy work, but the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work, thou, nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maid servant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hollowed it. Honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shalt not kill.
Thou shalt not commit adultery. Thou
shalt not steal. Thou shalt not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shalt not covet thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
wife, nor as man's servant, nor as
maid's servant, nor as ox, nor as nor
anything that is thy neighbors. I read
Exodus 20:es
1-17. May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of his word. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen. Amen.
So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the long scripture
questions, the vague questions as well
as the questions of debate. We are not
here to debate. We are here to spread
the true gospel of Jesus. So please be
as direct as possible with your
questions so we can be as direct as
possible with our answers out of the
King James Bible. No other Bibles or
books will be acknowledged on this
program. Also, keep in mind this is a
live stream, so feel free to send in
your questions that pertain to
everlasting life. We just ask that you
keep your questions to a two scripture
maximum. But let me introduce you the
family that's on the panel this evening.
We got brother Jerome, rest in peace.
Brother Julius, good evening everybody.
Brother Dre, good evening. Brother
James, good evening everyone. Sister
Deborah, good evening. Brother
Sean, and we have the guest caller with
us. And I'm brother Cornell. Sister
Deborah, what is our first question of
the evening? Yes, there are several held
over questions that will be answered
first before getting into tonight's Q&A.
So, uh, Jennifer Love asks in Luke
22:es 22- 24, since no one is in heaven
or the lake of fire, these scriptures
are to come. Lazarus and Abraham bosom
is this future.
All right, brother Dre, we know no one
is in heaven or in the lake of fire. So,
Dre, what you say?
Yeah. Um, Luke 22 is not the scripture
for that that that you speaking of. So,
you speaking of Luke 16. Let's go to
Luke 16 and read verses 20 to 23.
Okay. When you get there, go ahead,
brother.
Luke
16:20-23 says, "And there was a certain
beggar named Lazarus, which was laid at
his gate full of swords, and desiring to
be fed with the crumbs which fell from
the rich man's table. Moreover, the dogs
came and licked his swords. And it came
to pass that the beggar died and was
carried by the angels into Abraham's
bosom. The rich man also died and was
buried."
and in and in hell he lift up his eyes
being in torments and seeth Abraham a
far off and Lazarus in his bosom. So So
none of these things could have happened
already. They uh Abraham let's let let's
look at the the
uh some say Abraham is in heaven and the
rich man is in the grave. But let's go
to John 3 and read verse 13. John 3
and13.
Okay. John 3 and13 says, "And no man
hath ascended up to heaven, but he that
came down from heaven, even the son of
man which is in heaven." So this hasn't
taken place. If if if something like
this is to happen, it will be in the
future. Not not now. It hasn't happened.
Now, let's go see where Abraham is now.
Let's go to Genesis
25. Genesis
25 and read verses 8 and 9. When you get
there, go ahead, brother. Genesis
25 8 and 9 say, "Then Abraham gave up
the ghost and died in a good old age, an
old man and full of years, and was
gathered to his people. and his sons
Isaac and Ishmael buried him in the cave
of Machella in the field of Ephron the
son of Zohar the Hittite which is before
Mamry. So Abraham died and his children
Isaac and Ishmael buried him. So Abraham
is in the grave. Now let's go to
Ecclesiastics 9 real quick.
Ecclesiastics 9 and we going to read
verses
4-6. Ecclesiastics 9 4-6. Go ahead.
For to him that is joined to all the
living there is hope. For a living dog
is better than a dead lion. For the
living know that they shall die, but the
dead know not anything. Neither have
they anymore a reward. For the memory of
them is forgotten.
Also their love and their hatred and
their envy is now perished. Neither have
they any more a portion forever in
anything that is done under the sun. So
they not in the grave talking. None of
these things are happening. Skip down to
verse 10. Go ahead. Whatsoever thy hand
findeth to do, do it with thy might. For
there is no work, nor device, nor
knowledge, nor wisdom in the grave,
whether thou goest. So the the lake of
fire will not take place until after the
first resurrection and the white throne
judgment. And you can read about that in
Revelations
uh 19 and Revelation 20. And you can
also read about those that will be can
go and see somebody in that fire in
Isaiah 66. I hope that helped.
All right. Yes, sir. Brother Dre, that
was a good catch. Even though they
quoted the wrong scripture for you to
take them to the right scripture.
Thank you for that, brother. And guess
right
ahead. Look here. See, the rich
man is going is in the lake of fire.
Those are the people that didn't make
the first
resurrection. So, I want to go into
Revelation 20 chapter and show something
here. We going to read the uh uh
Revelation 20 and read four and five.
Yeah. Okay. Revelation 24 and5 says,
"And I saw thrones, and they sat upon
them, and judgment was given unto them.
And I saw the souls of them that were
beheaded for the witness of Jesus, and
for the word of God, and which had not
worshiped the beast, neither his image,
neither had received his his mark upon
their foreheads or in their hands. And
they lived and reigned with Christ a
thousand years."
But the rest of the But the rest of the
dead live not again until the thousand
years were finished. This is the first
resurrection.
Blessed.
Go ahead. Finish it. Blessed and holy is
he that hath part in the first
resurrection. On such the second death
have no power, but they shall be priests
of God and of Christ, and shall reign
with him a thousand years.
Now this is telling us that uh when
Jesus come and have the first
resurrection only the people the saints
are going that that have made it is
going to meet him in the air. Abraham is
one of them. Yes. And Lazarus will be
one of them. But the rich man won't come
out of the ground for a thousand years
later after Jesus done rule this
earth. So how can they be together?
after we're a thousand years later and
after the white throne judgment and then
he's thrown in the lake of fire. So if
the conversation went on between him and
Abraham that was after the white throne
judgment and after the last resurrection
I just wanted to point that out. And
verses seven tells you that that's after
the thousand years. And then you read
verses 11 all the way through 15 and
it'll tell you about the lake of fire
after the white throne judgment. There
you go. That's it. Okay. All right.
Thank you for that. And we hope that
that answered that question. And
remember, blessed and holy is he that
have part in that first resurrection.
All right, we're going to move on to our
next question. Next question. Asher
asks, "Who or why are there people in
heaven in Revelation 19 verse1?"
Revelation 19 and one. Who or why are
there people in heaven? Brother Julius,
uh, let's go there, James. Revelation 19
and one. And when you get it, go ahead
and read it.
And after these things, I heard a great
voice of much people in heaven saying,
"Hallelujah. Salvation and glory and
honor and power unto the Lord our God."
Now, I want to piggyback off what
brother Dre and the guest caller says.
The this is an analogy of the future. If
you read Revelation 20 and one, John
said, "I saw." If you read Revel chapter
21, he'll say, "I saw." So, let's go and
show you Revelation the first
chapter. Revelation the first uh first
chapter, the Lord called things as if
they are, but they haven't happened yet.
Revelation one. And when you get it,
look what he said. Because the Lord uh
John the whole book of revelation John
wrote the book of revelation but it is
uh uh it's future when you get it
revelation 21 and read verse
uh nine 9 and 10. So Revelation 21 I'm
sorry Revelation 1 9 and 10. Okay. Show
you how how the Lord worked. He called
things. Go ahead.
I John who also am your brother and
companion in tribulation and in the
kingdom and patience of Jesus Christ was
in the aisles that is called Patmos for
the word of God and for the testimony of
Jesus Christ. He was there on the island
of Patmos for the word of God and for
the testimony. And the Lord projected
John to in his mind's eye to the future.
He showed him the future. Now this ain't
happened yet.
Look what happens at verse 10. I was in
the spirit of the Lord on the Lord's day
and heard behind me a great voice as of
a trumpet. So now he said he was in the
spirit on the Lord's day. That's the
that's that is the day of the Lord when
the Lord begins to inter uh reign into
the affair interferes into the affairs
of men. Let's go to Revelation the 12th
chapter because like Dre said in St.
John the third chapter. You can read
that again on your own. No man has
ascended in the in the heaven. There are
no people in
heaven. This is uh a vision that he saw.
Revelation Revelation the 12th chapter,
my brother, and pick this
up.
Uh verse 12, I'm uh chapter 12 verse
one. Revelation 121. Go ahead. And there
appeared a great wonder in heaven, a
woman clothed with the sun, and the moon
under her feet, and upon her head a
crown of 12 stars. Now, you can go to
Genesis chapter 37 and verse 9, and it
would tell you who the sun, the stars,
and the moon, the 12 tribes, uh,
including Joseph, um, his mother, and
his father, Israel. But it's a vision of
the future. Continue read uh brother and
she being with child cried travailing in
birth and paying to be delivered. So now
he showed you the future. This is
something in the future what's going to
happen in the future. Nobody's up in
heaven. But now let me show you when
what happened when the Lord returns.
Let's go to first Corinthians the 15th
chapter. And that was very good answer
brother Dre. and and guest
caller. Nobody's up in heaven. 1
Corinthians the 15th chapter when you
get it, my
brother, pick this up. When the Lord
will come, when he come and pick it up
in verse 20,
okay, that says, "But now is Christ
risen from the dead and become the first
fruits of them that slept." Go ahead.
For since by man came death, by man came
also the resurrection of the dead. Go
ahead. For as in Adam all die, even so
in Christ shall all be made alive. Shall
all be made alive? Not already. Shall
all be made alive. But when? But every
man in his own order. Uh-huh. Christ the
first fruits. Afterward they that are
Christ at his coming. Now let's go to
first Thessalonians the 4th chapter and
look at when these uh when they going to
come. Nobody gets nothing until the Lord
returns. Sisters and brothers and this
we have to understand. There are no
people in heaven. The book said the dead
knoweth not anything. First
Thessalonians chapter
4 and pick this up at verse
14. Verse 13. 13. Go ahead. But I would
not have you to be ignorant, brethren,
concerning them which are asleep, that
ye sorrow not, even as others have no
hope.
Go ahead. For if we believe that Jesus
died and rose again, even so them also
which sleep in Jesus will God bring with
him. when we just read it in 1
Corinthians the 15th chapter at his
coming cuz the dead is going to rise the
righteous going to be changed. Go ahead
brother. For this we say unto you by the
word of the Lord that we will we which
are alive and remain until the coming of
the Lord shall not prevent them which
are asleep. Notice what Paul said until
the coming of the Lord. Continue. For
the Lord himself shall descend from
heaven with a shout, with the voice of
the archangel, and with the trump of
God, and the dead in Christ shall rise
first. Because the seventh trumpet
announces the return of the Lord, the
resurrection of the dead, the changing
of the righteous uh from mortal to
immortal. Sisters and brothers, now then
what happens? Go ahead, brother. 17 Then
we which are alive and remain shall be
caught up together with them in the
clouds to meet the Lord in the air. And
now this cloud or go ahead finish that
James. And so shall we be ever ever be
with the Lord. And Zechariah the 14th
chapter will tell you where he going to
be. He going to feed his feet just
standing that day with his saints upon
the mount of olives. But we going to be
caught up with him in the clouds, which
is the second heaven, sisters and
brothers. Everything above the ground uh
uh uh uh is considered the second
heaven. The third heaven no man can see
or approach like Dread. So Revelation 19
and one these these people uh met the
Lord in the clouds and they're making
all these statements. If you read the
rest of it, we coming down with the Lord
with him, sisters and brothers. But we
met him in the clouds, which is the
second heaven. But no man, there are no
people in heaven. Anybody else want to
add to that?
Oh, brother, other than what you said,
no man has ascended to heaven except for
he that came down and died for the sins
of the world. That's the only one. And
when we come down with him, that's what
we going to be saying when we come down.
We have overcome now. Power and glory
and honor to him. that. So this that's
what these people are saying in
Revelation 19 and this is what John is
seeing. He is seeing the future. I hope
that helped.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next
question. Next question. Dr. Rock
Productions asks, "Is it okay to eat
dinner at someone's home if there is an
urn in their home?"
Um I haven't seen any scriptures that
say you couldn't. That is your choice.
But the food is
unclean and you unclean when you go into
the house whether you eat or not. And so
also the food is unclean. And sometimes
you have people that they go to funerals
and they have a repass in a funeral home
and they got all the food there. That
food is unclean. Sometimes you got
people that have barbecues and picnics
and cemeteries. That food is unclean.
You are unclean. So, as a personal
choice, absolutely not. And I think I'm
speaking for the panel also that we
would choose not to do that. But,
however, if you decide to do that, um, I
think you should, you know, get some
wisdom and then inform the person that's
inviting you over of what the scriptures
say about their house is continually
unclean and so is their food unclean.
And maybe that may put a little spark in
them to get rid of that earn. But let's
go into Numbers the 19th chapter.
Numbers the
19th. Because the Lord want us to do
this thing exactly the way he said it
and cut out all the creativity and
exceptions to the
rule. Numbers 19. And let's pick it up
at verse
14. Go ahead, brother.
This is the law. When a man dieth in a
tent, all that come into the tent, and
all that is in the tent shall be unclean
seven days. Mhm. And every open vessel
which had no covering bound upon it is
unclean.
Mhm. And whosoever touches one that is
slain with a with a sword in the open
fields or a dead body or a bone of a man
or a grave shall be unclean seven days.
So you see that that ern has got that
house continually unclean because it is
like a small casket but it's in ashes
form still considered to be a body and
is still considered to be unclean the
food as well as the visit that you may
make there. But let's go into Genesis
the third chapter genes Genesis 3 and
let's read one verse there brother
Genesis 3 and let's see what the Lord
said here.
And that verse 19, Genesis 3 and 19,
what did the Lord say? In the sweat of
thy face shalt thou eat bread, till thou
return unto the ground, for out of it
was thou taken, for dust thou art, and
to and to dust shalt thou return. So
being that the Lord created us all and
he said he created us out of the dust of
the ground and he said that hey for dust
thou art and unto dust shall thou return
no one should have a earn in their home.
Everyone should return the ashes to the
ground as the Lord just said in that
Genesis 3 and verse 19 and not to be
creative and put it in necklaces and
rings and earrings. The Lord say don't
return it into your closet or your home
or jewelry or none of that. Just return
it back to the ground like the Lord
said. And every home that has an earn,
please do what does says the Lord and
return those ashes back to the ground.
And that's all I
got. And we hope that that answered your
question there, Sister Deborah, as we
move on to the next one. Moving on. Miss
White at Miss White asked you to explain
Ecclesiastes 3 verse
21 what these two spirits talked about
here. All right. So in
Ecclesiastes 3 and verse 21 that book
right after Proverbs pick it up there
brother at that verse 21 and the death
caller will take it from there.
No, we're not going to pick it up there.
Okay. What we going to do, you know what
we going to do is we going to back up
the verse uh uh
uh 18 verse and we going to read down.
So we going to get us some sense out of
this verse 18. Okay, go ahead.
Ecclesiastes
3:18 says, "I said in my heart
concerning the state of the sons of men
that God might manifest them and that
they might see that they themselves are
beast."
Now, now right here, God God is letting
know letting us know that we in his eyes
are just like beast. We don't have
preeminence. Now, look at what he said.
Now, I compares us. Go ahead.
For that which befallth the sons of men
befallth beast, even one thing befallth
them. As the one dieth, so dieth the
other. Yay, they have all one breath, so
that a man hath no preeminence over a
beast, for all is vanity.
There's one die, so so does we. So man
say they all have one breath.
Go ahead. Verse 20 says, "All go unto
one place. All are of the dust, and all
turn to the dust
again." Uh, "Who knoweth the spirit of
man that goeth upward, and the spirit of
the beast that goeth downward to the
earth." Now, now let's let's see what
this spirit is. Like I said, we all
return to the dust. The man returned to
the dust and the spirit returned to the
dust. So we got to find out what spirit
is talking about. So let's go into Job
the 27th chapter and start reading at
verse one.
Okay, Job 27.
Job 27 and verse one says, "Moreover,
Job continued his parable and said, "As
God liveth, who hath taken away my
judgment, and the Almighty who hath
vexed my
soul, all the while my breath is in me,
and the spirit of God is in my
nostrils."
Wait a minute. The spirit of God where
is in my nostrils.
Okay. So then the breath you breathe
that's talking about in your nostril to
make sure that he's talking about in his
nostril. Go to Genesis the second
chapter and read verse 7. Okay. Genesis
2 and 7 says, "And the Lord God formed
man of the dust of the ground and
breathed into his nostrils the breath of
life and man became a living soul."
Oh, so the the the the spirit in your
nostril is the breath of life. That's
what that's that's breath and that's
what you breathe. Yep. Yes, sir.
Now, let's go back and read Ecclesiastes
3 and 21.
Okay. Ecclesiastes 3 and 21. Sorry, I
left out my space. But 3 and 21 says,
"Who knoweth the spirit of man that
goeth upward and the spirit of the beast
that goeth downward to the earth?"
Now that's a question he asked, didn't
it? Who know it? You know, like, have
anybody ever seen it? You ain't never
seen breath, right? Nope. Let me show
you what happened. Let's go into
Ecclesiastes the 12th chapter. This the
last place. Okay.
And uh we going to pick it up and we
going to get right to the
point.
Uh verse
13. No, that's not it. Let's
see where it say verse seven.
Maybe verse seven. Let me see. Let's
see. Yeah. Verse seven. I'm sorry. Verse
seven. What's it say? Yep. Then shall
the dust return to the earth as it was,
and the spirit shall return unto God who
gave it. Donai, he dug man out of dust
of the ground, breathe into his nostril,
the breath of life. Man became a living
soul. Man die, he go back to the ground.
Then the breath which is also the spirit
in your nostrils go back to God who gave
it. And the question is that Solomon
asked who know it whether the breath of
God of man goes up or the breath of the
go beast go down. We know we know that
the breath go back to God that gave it.
That's all I have to say. All right.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next next one. Aspirin
Israel says in Daniel 12
11-13, I understand the 1290 days in
verse 11. What is the significance of
the 1335 days in verse 12?
All right. So that's coming out of
Daniel the 12th
chapter. And let's go there, brother
James. And I guess caller will lead you
on where he'd like to go from there.
Okay. Daniel 12 11 through13 says, "And
from the time that the daily sacrifice
shall be taken away, and the abomination
that make it desolate set up, there
shall be a,00 290 days.
Blessed is he that waiteth and cometh to
the,35 and 30 days. But go thou go thou
thy way till the end be for thou shalt
rest and stand in thy lot at the end of
the days.
Now the first thing is we tell Daniels
he's going to rest in other words die
until the end be until then you going to
stand in your lot that mean he going to
be raised at when the Lord at the end of
days like the Lord said four times in uh
uh uh uh in St. John that he's going to
raise you up at the last day. Now I can
only give
account for the 1260 days of great
tribulation and also the,040 days of
sacrifice which took place before this
great tribulation start because he
called the uh uh uh the false prophet is
going to cause the the tribulation to
cease. So now so that 1260 days at 1,040
days that covers time of the great
tribulation and the animal sacrifice.
Let's go into Daniel the 8th chapter and
we're going to start reading at verse 9
and we're going to read down to 14.
Okay. Daniel
8:E9
says, "And out of one of them came forth
a little horn which waxed exceeding
great toward the south and toward
that little horn represent the false
prophet." But go ahead toward the east
and toward the pleasant land. And it
waxed great even to the host of heaven.
and it cast down some of the hosts and
of the stars to the ground and stamped
upon them.
Yay, he magnified himself even to the
prince of the host and by him the daily
sacrifice was taken away and the place
of his sanctuary was cast down.
Now that let you know that during that
three and a half years he gonna uh uh uh
cast some of the stars to the ground.
That mean he going to make war with the
saints and he going to prevail for them
three and a half years. And then it said
that they and he going and the daily
sacrifice is going to be cast out. He
going to stop the animal sacrifice that
the going to start. Go ahead
and read verse 12. And an host was given
him against the daily sacrifice by
reason of transgression and it cast down
the truth to the ground and it practiced
and prospered.
Then then I heard then I heard one saint
speaking and another saint said unto the
certain that certain saint which spake,
how long shall be the vision concerning
the daily sacrifice and the
transgression of desolation to give both
the sanctuary and the host to be trotten
underfoot.
So the question here is question here is
how long will it be concerning the daily
sacrifice and also the great tribulation
to be given underfoot. How long? How
much time? Go ahead and read. And he
said unto me unto
2,300 days then shall the sanctuary be
cleansed. And said and how is it the
sanctuary going to be cleansed? That's
when the Lord come. And let's go quickly
to second 2 second 2 second 2 second 2
second 2 second 2 second 2 second 2
second 2 second 2 second 2 second
Thessalonians 2 chapter and show you
when the Lord is going to stop this.
We're going to read 1 through 4 and skip
down to verse 8. Okay. Second
Thessalonians 2:es 1-4 and then 8.
Correct sir?
That's correct. Okay. It says, "Now we
beseech you, brethren, by the coming of
our Lord Jesus Christ, and by our
gathering together unto him, that ye be
not soon shaken in mind, or be troubled,
neither by spirit, nor by word, nor by
letter, as from us, as that the day of
Christ is at hand."
Let let no man deceive you by any means,
for that day shall not come, except
there be a falling away first, and the
man of sin be revealed, the son of
predition, who opposed and ex go ahead.
who opposed and exalted himself above
all that is called God or that is
worshiped so that he as God siteth in
the temple of God showing himself that
he is
God. So now this is the same guy that we
just read about in the eth chapter of
Daniel. He going to build a temple. He
going to get in it and he going to show
himself as God. But when is he going to
be terminated? Skip down to verse eight
and read it. And then shall the wicked
be revealed whom the Lord shall consume
with the spirit of his mouth and shall
destroy with the brightness of his
coming.
Now all I have to say where it says
blessed those that lasted that
particular amount of days. But I don't
know where to put them. All I know is
the 2300 days covers daily sacrifice,
great tribulation. Uh if you find
yourself living after that, how many
days
later, then you're
blessed. That's all I can give you on
that. I don't know what to do with those
extra days. I don't know whether to put
them in the front, in the middle, or
behind. I have to say, I hope that
answered your question there. As we move
on to our next question with a time
check. Yes, the time is
8:07. Gloria Jose says,
"Exactly, how many days did our savior's
Emmanuel stay on the earth after his
resurrection and how many days after was
he accepted by the father?"
All right, Jerome, share some light.
Well, I'm going to break it down uh
because it's two questions there. So,
I'm going to break it down um into two
questions. Uh the first one let's deal
with. Let's go to Acts the first
chapter. Exactly how many days did our
savior and manuel which we know is Jesus
Christ stay in the earth after his
resurrection? Go to Acts the first
chapter and read verse 2 and three.
Okay. It says, "Until the day in which
he was taken up, after that he through
the Holy Ghost had given commandments
unto the apostles whom he had
chosen, to whom also he showed himself
alive after his passion by many
infallible proofs, being seen of them 40
days, and speaking of the things
pertaining to the kingdom of God." So
it's after he u resurrected from the
dead. Okay. He was seen alive in his
spirit body, you know, for 40 days
before he went back to heaven and and
and and he's sitting on the right hand
of the father. Okay. Now, um the second
part of that question was uh read that
read that second part again for me. Yes.
How many days after was he accepted by
the father? Okay. So he has to come out.
He has to be resurrected from the
ground. And according to the script, he
got to come out that ground on the
Sabbath day. And we know he came out
that ground on the Sabbath day just
before sundown. Okay? And that sundown
will be the beginning of the first day
of the week. So the reason why I'm
mentioning that cuz I want to show that
Jesus is the first
fruit and he got to be accepted on the
tomorrow after the Sabbath which will be
a Sunday. So let's go let's go to first
Corinthians the 15th chapter verse 20
and then we going to tie with Leviticus
23.
1 Corinthians 15 verse 20. Yeah. Says,
"But now is Christ risen from the dead
and become the first fruits of them that
slept." All right. So, he the first
fruit and the first fruit got to come
out on the Sabbath day just before
Sunday. That's why we going to uh look
at the New Testament and establish that.
But before we do that, go to Leviticus
23.
Okay? And read verse 10 and 11. Okay? It
says, "Speak unto the children of
Israel, and say unto them, when ye be
come into the land which I give unto
you, and shall reap the harvest thereof,
then ye shall bring a sheath of the
first fruits of your harvest unto the
priest."
And he shall wave the sheath before the
Lord to be accepted for you. On the
tomorrow after the Sabbath, the priest
shall wave it. Yeah. And that tomorrow
will be the first day of the week which
we call Sunday. Okay. So now let's go to
St. John chapter
20. St. John chapter 20 and read
verse 17 was this is when uh he had came
out of that grave.
Okay. And he showed himself in Mary
Magdalene
song. Read that 17.
It says, "Jesus saith unto her, touch me
not, for I am not yet ascended to my
father, but go to my brethren and say
unto them, I ascend unto my father and
your father and to my God and your God."
So this happened on Sunday, right? But
he said, "Don't touch me yet cuz I ain't
been up there to be accepted cuz I'm the
first fruit." He got to check me and
make sure that everything is where it's
supposed to be. All right. Then after
that, he going to come back. But your
question is when did he come back? Well,
this is Sunday. Now, let's establish
when he came back. So, let's tie it with
the Matthews
28. After he was accepted on Sunday,
when did he come back? Matthew's 28 and
pick it up at verse 9, read to the 10.
Okay, it says, "And as they went to tell
his disciples, behold, Jesus met them,
saying, All hell. And they came and held
him by the feet and worshiped him. Then
said Jesus unto them, Be not afraid. Go
tell my brethren that they go into
Galilee, and there shall they see me."
Remember he said he was seen of his
brethren and of the disciples and a
whole lot of other people we know Mary
saw him right so the reason why I'm
quoting this verse is before he said
touch me
not and that was
Sunday okay so now when he returned they
handling them and they touching them
okay and this happened it was still the
first day of the
week right around the daytime part of
the first day of the week
Sunday. Okay, that's all I got on there.
If anybody want to add something.
All right, thank you for that, brother.
Good light as we move on to our next
question. Yes, and the time is
8:13. Anthony Garado
uh asks, "What study approach do you all
use daily by subject, by book, by
section, using a concordance?"
So, Brother Dream, what's your style
when it comes to that study, brother?
Prayer.
Yes, sir. And
persistence. You know, the Bible tells
you to have a holy convocation. I
learned so much coming to the Israel of
God and coming with a pad, a
pen, taking
notes, asking
questions, going over the questions,
going over the notes, talking to
people. Let's let's go to uh Isaiah 28
and look at something here. Isaiah 28
and verse 9.
But you you have many tools now you
could use. You got Bible apps. You can
think about a word that's in the
scripture. You might not know where it
is. And you could type that word in and
it'll bring up all the scriptures where
that word is that will help assist you.
But it's better to really dig into this
book because then you get it from off
the phone into your heart and your mind.
That's where you want it at. So I would
encourage that. But uh Isaiah 28 and
pick it up at verse 9, brother.
Whom shall he teach knowledge? And whom
shall he make to understand doctrine?
Them that are weaned from the milk and
drawn from the
breast? For precept must be upon
precept, precept upon precept, line upon
line, line upon line. here a little and
there a little. So the the word you you
desire the sincere milk of the word and
you grow thereby and precept upon
precept, line upon line, here a little
and there a little. So you go one place
and it verifies another place that you
may go to for verification's sake. But
let's let's go to uh 1 Timothy 4. 1
Timothy
4 and read verse 13 and we gonna skip.
First Timothy 4 and13.
1 Timothy 4 and13 says till I come give
attendance to reading to exhortation to
doctrine. So you give attendance to
reading. That means you studying and you
exhorting what it is you
studying and the doctrine. Right? Now
skip down to verse
15. Meditate upon these things. Give
thyself holy to them that thy profiting
may appear to all. So you meditate on
it. You know, Psalms tell you when you
meditate on the law day and night, you
be like a tree planted by the rivers of
waters. Yes, sir. So, that will indeed
be a blessing to you. Go ahead, brother.
Take heed unto thyself and into the
doctrine. Continue in them, for in doing
this, thou shalt both save thyself and
them that hear thee. That's right. Take
heed to what you learning and continue
in that word. And in doing that, you
will save yourself and all that hear
thee. Um, if anybody want to add, go
right ahead.
Yeah. You know, Brother Dre, another
good style, too. Some people have never
read the book from cover to cover.
Yes, sir. It's good to start at Genesis
1 and read it all the way down to
Revelation 22. see how long it take you.
Challenge yourself and you know we hope
that you receive a lot of understanding
out of that. That's another style too.
Absolutely, brother. Absolutely.
All right. So, we hope that that
answered your question as we continue to
move right on along. Yes. Moving on. Uh
the time is 8:17.
Uh, Jennifer Love asks, "Can the lineage
of each of the 12 tribes be traced back
to their
fathers?" All right, brother Jerome shed
some light on this lineage being traced
back.
Um, absolutely.
Um, you can trace it's it's 12 tribes of
Israel which are the children of Jacob.
He the one had the 12 sons which are the
12 tribes of Israel. So we know we can
trace them back to their
father. And if you can trace them back
to their father Jacob, then you can also
trace
Jacob back to his father which is Isaac.
And then you can take trace Isaac back
to to his father which is
Abraham. Okay. So let's go to first
Chronicles chapter one.
and pick it up at verse 27. Read to the
28. Then we going to skip. Okay. Uh 1
Chronicles 1:27 says, "Abram, the same
is Abraham,
the sons of Abraham, Isaac, and
Ishmael." There go Isaac. You traced him
back to you traced him to Abraham,
right? Skip down to verse 34.
And Abraham begat Isaac, the sons of
Isaac, Esau, and Israel. So now you just
traced Isaac to Abraham. Now you tracing
Israel, which we know his name was
Jacob, and it was changed to Israel. You
trace him back to his father right
there. Okay? So, you know, you can go to
Exodus chapter 1 and read verse 1-5 and
you got all 12 tribes listed and say,
"These are the ones that came out of the
loins of
Jacob." Okay, that's all I got on.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we continue to move right along,
moving right along. Time is 8:19.
Glirious Glenn Sirius asks, "Can you
take part in the feast of unleaven bread
if you have not taken the Passover?"
So, guest caller, can you take part in
the feast of unleaven bread if you have
not taken the Passover?
Well, there's not there's nothing
written that said that you can't. But I
know one
thing. You're supposed to eat unleven
bread for seven days.
So if you missed the Passover, whether
you can keep it or not, there's nothing
written. So I can't tell you nothing
about it.
Deal. If you don't eat unleaven bread
for seven days, the Lord say you're
going to be cut off from among your
brethren. So you take that for whatever
it's
worth. All right.
Hope that answers your question as we
move on to our next one. Yes. Moving on.
And the time is
8:21. Jennifer Love asks, "Does God
speak to
non-believers? Had had a person tell me
that God told them to tell me something?
Wouldn't God speak directly to me versus
a non-believer?"
Hey, Brother Julius, can God kind of
speak to who he choose?
Does God speak to non-believers? Yeah,
he speak to everybody through his
written
word and he speaks uh um and when
somebody tell you like somebody told me
um that somebody uh brother Julius the
Lord sent me to you to tell you
something but I tried her against the
book and I know the Lord didn't send
her. So you got to be careful with what
people tell you that God sent them uh uh
sent them to you and then you got to ask
them where's that written at. Let me
show you something here. Let's go to
Matthew the 4th chapter
first. Matthew chapter
4. Because you got a whole lot of people
that said God spoke to
them and said this and said that and a
whole lot of them God a spoke to them.
Jeremiah the 23rd chapter said these
preachers ran, these false prophets ran,
but God said he didn't send them.
Matthew 4:4 and this is for everybody. I
mean this is for everybody in the
creation. Matthew 4 and4 when you get it
brother James go ahead. But he answered
and said it is written man shall not
live by bread alone but by every word
that proceedth out of the mouth of God.
Even the nonbelievers who claim that
they don't believe in God. They believe
they don't want to acknowledge it or
confess it because they spent a whole
lifetime denying what they don't believe
in. So they believe in something. It is
written, "Man shall not live by bread
alone, but by every word that proceed
out of the mouth of God." Now, but how
they going to hear it? How do you reach
a non-believer? What? And uh let's look
at Romans the third
chapter. Romans chapter 3. Well, I don't
believe in God. Oh, it don't matter
whether you to believe or not. You still
living by his word and it is his air
that you are breathing.
Romans
3 and read verse three and four. James,
for what if some did not believe? What
if some people don't What if some don't
believe? Go ahead. Shall their unbelief
make the faith of God without effect? Go
ahead. God forbid. That means no. Go
ahead. Yay. Let God be true, but every
man a liar. As it is written. As it is
what? As it is written, everywhere we
go, everything is written. Go ahead.
That thou mightest be justified in thy
sayings, and mightest overcome when thou
art judged. So now Paul is quoting Psalm
51. Psalm 51 and verse4. Let me show you
something else. Romans the 10th chapter.
We already in Romans. Romans the 10th
chapter.
Okay. Romans 10 and read 14 and 15.
Romans 10. 14- 15. Do God speak to
non-believers? Yeah. He said through his
word. Whether they believe it or not,
it's up to them. When you get it, my
brother, read 14 and 15. How then shall
they be called on? I'm sorry. How then
shall they call on him in whom they have
not believed? Yeah. And how shall they
be How shall they believe in him whom
they have not heard? You got to hear
something to believe something. Go
ahead.
And how shall they hear without a
preacher? Go ahead. And how shall they
preach except they be sent? So you got
to have a preacher that's sent by God.
Now back up and read verse eight. You
can read the rest of it on your own, but
read verse eight. But what saith it? But
say what? Go ahead. The word is nigh
thee, even in thy mouth and in thine
heart. That is the word of faith which
we preach. My last place, St. John the
20th chapter. You got to hear the
word. I don't go to church. I don't
believe. It doesn't matter. You're still
living by every written word of
God. St. John 20. And I got one verse
there. St. John 20. My brother James and
read verse because Thomas didn't believe
either. And he was one of Jesus'
apostles
disciples. 20 and uh verse
30. and many other signs truly did Jesus
in the presence of his disciples which
are not written in this book. So he did
some things that are not written in this
book but verse 31 go ahead James but
these are written that ye might believe
that Jesus is the Christ the son of God
and that believing ye might have life
through his name. So does God speak to
non-believers? He speaks to everybody
through his written word. Sometime he'll
send an angel but uh he but primarily
through his word sisters and brothers.
Now if somebody tell you that God sent
him to tell you something first of all
if it's a female is her head
covered like the one that came to me her
head wasn't covered and she claimed that
she was a prophetist and a pastor but I
wait her. There are no female pastors in
the Bible and every woman that's praying
or prophesying must have her head
covered and whatever she's speaking to
me must be
written out of this book. That's all I
got. Anybody want to add to that?
Yeah. Brother Julius, somebody come and
tell you something. The Lord tell us
also, believe not every spirit, but try
the spirits whether or not they are from
God. But how do you try them? You got to
have a a a source to go to to read what
what what shows them to be a a a prophet
or a prophetess of God or no.
Yeah. And this book right here because
Jesus told you man should not live by
bread alone but by every word that
proceed out of the mouth of God. And
everything that he wanted us to know he
had it written in his book from Genesis
to Revelation. That's all I got.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next
question. Moving on. And the time is
8:27. She also asks, "I see that some of
the brothers that stand in the front of
the congregation hold some type of poll
staffs. What does this represent?"
All right. Well, we like to give a
better term of staff. So guest caller,
what does that represent when a brother
got a staff in his
hand? He
let because when Israel was a nation
also all the male
Israelites carriage st wherever they
went or whatever they got ready to do.
Now let's go further. Let's go into
Exodus 12th chapter when they were
getting ready to leave out of Egypt.
Exodus 12 and read verse 11.
Okay. Exodus 12 and verse 11 says, "And
thus shall ye eat it with your loins
girded, your shoes on your feet, and
your staff in your hand, and ye shall
eat it in haste. It is the Lord's
Passover."
You know, that was a normal thing for a
man to carry a staff. Let's go and and
and look at with David and Goliath.
Let's go to 1st Samuel the 17th chapter.
And we're going to read 38 and 40 and
skip down to 43.
1st
Samuel 17 and what was the verse again,
sir?
38 to 40. Then we're going to skip down
to
Okay.
38-40 says, "And Saul armed David with
his armor, and he put an helmet of brass
upon his head, and also he armed him
with a coat of ma
male." And David girded his sword upon
his armor, and he is said to go, for he
had not proved it. And David said unto
Saul, I cannot go with these, for I have
not proved them. And David put them off
him. And he took his staff in his hand,
and chose him five smooth stones out of
the brook, and put them in a shepherd's
bag, which he had even in a script. And
his sling was in his hand. And he drew
near to the
Philistine. And down to 40.
Skip down to 40.
That was 40. You're finished, right?
Correct, sir.
Down to 43. Okay. And the Philistines
said unto David, "Am I a dog that thou
comest to me with staves?" And the
Philistine cursed David by his gods.
A stave was a staff because there other
time when people use that Israel uh
males in Israel got in in battle, they
use that staff to disarm their enemies.
So all the male of Israel carried a
stamp, but we just do it on the high
days in commemoration of what we was a
nation when we know who we was and when
we when we was in our own
country. So the ones with the staff were
just reliving what we did when we was a
nation. That's all I have to say. Guest
caller, can we go can we go to guest
caller? Can we go to Zechariah 8 and one
verse? Verse 4.
Go ahead.
Zechariah 8 and verse4. And this is yet
future.
Zechariah 8 and verse4 says, Yes, sir.
Thus sayeth the Lord of hosts, there
shall yet old men and old women dwell in
the streets of Jerusalem and every man
with his staff in his hand for very age.
So like guest caller said, it was common
for Israel to have the all the men to
have
staffs. That's why you saw Moses with
one in his hand. Even on that that pagan
picture, the ten commandments, even
Moses had a staff.
And when you get to be very a and start
getting up there, it's a good leaning
post.
All right, we hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Yes, the time is
8:32. Cool Blue asks, "What made Lucifer
really turn to wickedness? Was it God
making us?" All right, Julius, what you
say?
We going to see what the book say. Let's
go to Isaiah the 14th
chapter. One of the one of the morning
stars that rebelled against
God. Isaiah 14. Brother James. Isaiah
14, we gonna read verses 12 to 14. Okay.
How art thou? Go ahead, brother. How art
thou fallen from heaven, oh Lucifer, son
of the morning? How art thou cut down to
the ground, which didest weaken the
nations. Uh-huh. For thou hast said in
thine heart, your mind,
I will ascend into heaven. I will exalt
my throne above the stars of God. I will
sit also upon the mount of the
congregation in the sides of the north.
I will ascend above the heights of the
clouds. I will be like the most high.
Uh-uh. Uh-uh. You are a cherubim angel,
a serving angel, and you will be you
want to be like the most high. Ezekiel
the 28th chapter. And this will be it.
his pride and his ambition and
desires. That's what that iniquity was
found in him. Ezekiel 28, we're going to
read 14 and 15 and 17. Ezekiel
28. 14 and 15, my brother, when you get
it, go ahead. Thou art the anointed
cherub that coverth, and I have set thee
so. Thou was upon the holy mountain of
God. Thou has walked up and down in the
midst of the stones of fire. Thou was
perfect in thy ways from the day that
thou was created till iniquity was found
in thee. Iniquity is sin. Go ahead. What
verse was that? That was 15. Read verse
17. Thine heart was lifted up because of
thy beauty. Thou has corrupted thy
wisdom by wisdom by reason of thy
brightness. Uh-huh. I will I will cast
thee to the ground. I will lay thee
before kings that they may behold thee.
And that's so that's what got him messed
up. His pride, ambition, and uh desires
caused him to rebel. And that's why he
told the woman in the garden of Eden.
But God don't know that in the day that
you know, how do you know? He knew the
plan of God. He going to make this man
out of dust. And eventually all the
angels are gonna uh serve this
man. Serve his spirits. That's all I
got. Yep. So, Satan chose to be wicked.
Yep. From Lucifer, lightbringer to Satan
destructs, destroyer.
All right. Hope that answered your
question. Our next question. Yes. Time
8:35.
Most love says, "When I was in church
the morning of my baptism, I heard an
angelica voice. It said, "The
uncleanness of my body you can have, but
my soul dwells with the Lord. I was wide
awake." What could it have been?
Yes, caller. What could it have been?
I don't have a clue.
All
right. So, we're going to continue to
move on. Moving on. Ephatha have two
questions. She wants you to explain
Proverbs
8 22 and
23. Who is this? She states, "I
understand Jesus was Jehovah before he
came in the flesh and was begotten in
the beginning." And she also wants you
to uh explain Proverbs
8 25 and 26 where it says, "I was
brought forth in both verses. Please
explain precept to show what was meant
by saying he was brought
forth. All right, let's go to Proverbs
8. And looks like they want some light
on 23 to 26 and then 25 and 26. But uh
let's turn it over to the guest
caller and he'll take it from there.
It would have been nice if somebody g me
some uh heads up. Let's go read it. What
is that? Okay. Proverbs
8:22-23 says, "The Lord possessed me in
the beginning of his way before his
works of old. I was set up from
everlasting from the beginning or ever
the earth was."
Look, let me get that. We have to back
up and read this because I
didn't. Now, it was Proverbs 8 and 22,
right? Correct, sir. Yeah.
Some background on that first.
2. You said 22, correct, sir?
Would you like me to reread the two
scripts? Read read verse one first. We
got to find out who is it that it's
talking about. Verse one.
Okay. That is Proverbs 8:1 which says,
"Doeth not wisdom cry and understanding
put forth her voice."
Uh-huh. Go ahead. She standeth in the
top of high places, by the way, in the
places of the
paths. She crith at the gates, and at
the entry of the city, at the coming in,
at the doors,
where unto you, oh men, I call, and my
voice is the sons of man.
Now this talking about sheep. Who is
this she? It says in the beginning
wisdom. Okay. Yes sir. Now we go down to
22.
Okay. The Lord possessed me in the
beginning of his way before his works of
old. I was set up from everlasting from
the beginning or ever the earth was.
Now so what the Lord possessed wisdom.
So wisdom sound like as a person, but
the Lord is using that as a as a
metaphor to let you know that God had to
be wise to create the earth. He had to
be wise to to set forth the heaven and
everything. He had to be wise in order
to do all the things that he's
doing. So who is this talking? It is
using wisdom as a person, but it's
really saying that God had to have
wisdom to do all that he did.
That was what verse what was the rest of
that verse? All right. The next one was
Proverb 8:25 and 26. What is meant by
saying he was brought forth?
Okay. Well, let's go look at it.
But but the one we just answered that's
talking about wisdom is not a person.
You know wisdom is not but the Lord used
that cuz if the Lord didn't have no
wisdom he couldn't have created
nothing. Now you said eight now and what
25 and 26.
Okay. Still it's still the same thing.
It is sir that the Lord
okay the whole chapter is dealing with
the the wisdom that the Lord possessed.
Yeah, that's it.
It wasn't a person. It was the wisdom
which God passed on to everybody to have
some uh uh uh have some knowledge and
understanding. Why tell you to get
wisdom and knowledge with all your
getting get understanding. So he's
talking about wisdom that was with him.
Otherwise, he would have been too dumb
to create anything. Had to be pretty
wise to take a pile of dirt and make man
out of it. Come on. Yes, sir. Right.
Put the moon and stars out there and
they ain't got a string or nothing to
hold them up. But still, they don't run
into one another and they don't fall.
That takes some real wisdom to do that.
Yeah. And the Lord had it from the
beginning. That's that verse 33. Uh
James, that verse uh 22, I'm sorry. 22
and 23.
The Lord possessed me in the beginning
of his way before his works of old. I
was set up from everlasting from the
beginning or ever the earth was. There
you go.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next Yes.
And the time is
8:42. We are now in
Pardon me. New territory. Yes. All
right. We are now into tonight's Q&A for
Wednesday, April the 23rd,
2025. Sai Amaru Israel says, "Please
help me to understand these two
commandments." Leviticus 19 verse
27 and Exodus 23 verse 19. Seething a
kid in mother's milk is it? If it is in
the Bible, I want to understand them so
I won't violate them. Any clarity would
be greatly appreciated.
All right, let's go in Leviticus 19.
I'm there.
Verse 27. And then next book would be
Exodus 23 and 19. And the guest caller
will share some light from there.
Okay. Leviticus 19 and 27 says, "Ye
shall not round the corners of your
heads, neither shalt thou mar the
corners of thy
beard." Then
um Exodus
23:19 says, "The first of the first
fruits of thy land thou shalt bring into
the house of the Lord thy God. Thou
shalt not see the kid in his mother's
milk.
This was asked uh ask a
much asked some much earlier and I give
you the same answer that I gave you
then. Ain't got no scripture to explain
none of
them. Don't seize a kid in his mother's
milk. What's that mean? Don't boil a a a
young goat in his mother's milk. I don't
know. Ain't nothing written to explain
that. The same thing, the corners of the
beard. I don't know what the corners of
the beard
is. All I know is we have to wear
beards.
All right. We should put put this
together because wearing a beard ain't
going to get you saved or cut off
because sin is the transgression of the
law. So, like I said several months ago,
I don't know what neither one of them
mean.
There's nothing in the scripture that
explain them other than what it
says. That's all I have to say. All
right, we'll leave it there. We're going
to move on to our next questions as time
is ticking and I'd like to open them up
to the panel. What is our next question?
Next question. AD says, "It seems that
Numbers
10:9 of blowing the trumpet to be saved
from our enemies is a clear instruction
from the Lord." If so, why don't we
apply it today?
Why don't we go to that numbers 10?
Okay. because also the trumpet was an
alarm. So let's uh read that and then
let's open it up to the panel. Okay.
Numbers 10 and9 says, "If ye go to war
in your land against the enemy that
oppresseth you, then ye shall blow an
alarm with the trumpets, and ye shall be
remembered before the Lord your God, and
ye shall be saved from your enemies."
And the first thing is we are slaves,
right?
We're not in our
land. Nope. And we don't control this
land. And we don't have no war against
nobody. It's this land against other
people. We are serving. We are here to
serve a sentence that God put on us put
on us because of what our forefathers
did. So why don't we blow a trumpet? For
what reason? We ain't got no nation to
defend. We don't have no country uh uh
uh uh to protect. We're
slaves. You go out and blow a trumpet,
you blow in the wrong place, you're
going to end up going to jail.
This don't apply to us right now. Once
when we go back to the land, so be it.
But trumpet is not But the trumpet also
announced the coming of the Lord.
Trumpet also announced the gathering
together of the people,
right?
That was for that end time. And and we
people too. What you say, brother Dre?
Ezekiel 33 lets you know that you warn
the people, but not by trumpet. It's the
word of God that is a warning to you to
turn from your ways. And that trumpet is
being blown all the time by way of the
word of God.
So it's not a physical thing right now.
You're not a nation.
Oh,
Trumpet doesn't apply to people that's
scattered and peeled at this time.
That's right, brother. Correct. That was
for that day and time when when our
people were in the land.
Like say through the trumpet of teaching
now. There you go.
Yep. Sound that alarm. Yes,
sir. All right. Going to move on to our
next one. Next question. Ni Jones asks,
"One, when will the marriage supper of
the lamb take place? And two, what
happened after the marriage supper of
the lamb?"
All right. So, finally, the supper of
the lamb. She asked when will that take
place? Take place and what happened
after the marriage supper of the lamb?
No scripture was given.
All right. And what happens after the
marriage supper of the lamb? Revelation
19.
Revelation 19.
Let's pick it up at verse 9 and then we
can um expound on it from there after
brother James reads that.
Revelation verse seven. Verse seven,
brother James.
Okay. It says, "Let us be glad and
rejoice and give honor to him, for the
marriage of the Lamb is come, and his
wife hath made herself
ready." And to her was granted that she
should be arrayed in fine linen, clean
and white, for the fine linen is the
righteousness of
saints. And he said unto me, "Write,
blessed are they which are called unto
the marriage supper of the Lamb." and he
saith unto me, these are the true
sayings of
God. So the
marri supper of the lamb don't come
don't start until Jesus
return. That's when it starts.
Yep. All right. It goes it goes and and
and uh uh and the very beginning of it
is in the wilderness where the Lord told
Israel first I'm going you unto me in
the wilderness that's marriage. Yeah.
And then this supper goes on this
marriage supper goes on for a thousand
years. And when the thousand years is
over with then the marriage supper of
the lamb is complete. All of them going
to be saint going to make it is going to
make it. And all of them that's not
going to make it is going to end up in
the lake of fire.
Marriage is marriage is nothing but a
covenant. In other words, he told Israel
in Ezekiel the 20th chapter, I'm going
to bring out from in fact, let's go look
at it. Go to Ezekiel the 20th chapter.
And we're going to start reading around
verse 35.
Okay. Ezekiel 20 and verse 35 says, "And
I will bring you into the wilderness of
the people, and there will I plead with
you face to face.
Like as I pleaded with your fathers in
the wilderness of the land of Egypt, so
will I plead with you, sayeth the Lord
God. And I will cause you to And I will
cause you to pass under the rod, and I
will bring you into the bond of the
covenant, and I will purge out
Mhm. Now, bringing you into the bond of
the covenant. What covenant? That's the
marriage covenant. And how do you come
into the bond of the covenant? by
getting baptized and then he say he
going to purge out the rebels but still
where is it I think it's Hosea Amos
which one is it where he say he going to
patrol you Hosea chapter 2
let's go look at it
pick it up around 14 okay I'm there uh
he says in Hosea
2:14 therefore behold I will allure her
and bring her into the wilderness and
speak comfortably unto to her. And I
will give her her vineyard from thence
and the valley of Acor for a door of
hope. And she shall sing there as in the
days of her youth, and as in the day
when she came out up out of the land of
Egypt. And it shall be at that day,
sayeth the Lord, that thou shalt call me
Ishi, and shalt call me no more bail.
For I will ple I
will mean my husband. Okay.
Mhm.
For I will take away the the names of
Balm out of her mouth, and they shall no
more be remembered by her name. And in
that day will I make a covenant for them
with the beast of the field, and with
the fowls of heaven, and with the
creeping things of the ground. And I
will break the bow, and the sword, and
the battle out of the earth, and will
make them to lie down safely. and I will
betroth thee unto me forever. Yay, I
will betroth thee unto me in
righteousness and in judgment and in
loving kindness and in mercies.
I
will use among men betroth me in
promise. But here it mean
marriage. That's why I'm going to you.
So it starts with with Israel in the
wilderness. Then the Lord go for a
thousand years and then he go to the
land once he come up out of the
wilderness and then he start to bringing
the whole world into the marriage uh uh
supper of the lamb. How do you do that?
By teaching them and bringing them into
the bond of the
company. Anybody have something else? Go
ahead with it.
I think that's it. But because the Lord
said he is married unto Israel. Yep.
And then even that even that la that
next verse the last one which which
explains the betroth as well. Verse 20
says, "I will even betroth thee unto me
in faithfulness and thou shalt know the
Lord."
Uh-huh. And that's when you going to
call him my husband. That's what the
word is mean.
Yeah.
Eventually, and eventually the whole
world will be brought in uh uh uh will
be uh take part in the marriage of the
lamb. And once that's over with, then he
going to turn it over to the father
going to have the white throne judgment.
The one that's going to make it that
didn't make it, they go into the lake of
fire. The ones that did, they're going
to be changed and they going to be God.
And then the father going to come down.
Let's answer both questions. Yes, sir.
Indeed. I'll see you at the
wedding. All
right. Moving on to our next one. Sister
Deborah's time is a ticking. Yes. Moving
on.
Malikure asks in Genesis 3 verse 6, "The
tree that was good for food, the one
that made one wise, the fruit that she
ate and gave to her husband, was those
things knowledge she received from
Satan?"
Forbidden knowledge. Why don't we go
there? Let's go to that. Genesis 3 and
verse 6.
Let's read that first and then let's
open it up to the pal. Okay. Genesis 3:6
says, "And when the woman saw that the
tree was good for food, and that it was
pleasant to the eyes, and a tree to be
desired to make one wise, she took of
the fruit thereof, and did eat, and gave
also unto her husband with her, and he
did eat."
Indeed. And the question again, Deborah,
was those things knowledge she received
from Satan?
When Jose said uh where you ate the
fruit of lies. Chapter 10 verse 13.
Hosea what? Chapter 10 verse 13.
Read it. It says Hosea 10:13 says, "Ye
have blowed wickedness. Ye have reaped
iniquity. Ye have eaten the fruit of
lies because thou didest trust in thy
way in the multitude of thy mighty
men. So that's the whole thing. Adam and
Eve ate the fruit of lion. Yes, wisdom,
sure, but it was perverted
wisdom because Satan told uh uh Eve she
wasn't going to die and she ate. That's
that Genesis back to back to Genesis 3
and that's what it is. So now let's show
you what Jesus said to eat. Let's go
into St. John the 6th
chapter. Start reading. I don't know.
Start reading at verse
uh 48. Okay.
John 6 and 48 says, "I am I am that
bread of life. Your fathers did eat mana
in the wilderness and are dead. This is
the bread which cometh down from heaven,
that a man may eat it thereof and not
die. I am the li I am the living bread
which came down from heaven. If any man
eat of this bread, he shall live
forever. And the bread that I will give
is my flesh, which I will give for the
law of the for the life of the world.
The Jew the Jews therefore strove among
themselves, saying, "How can this man
give us his flesh to eat?" Then Jesus
said unto them, "Verily, verily, I say
unto you, except ye eat the flesh of the
Son of Man, and drink his blood, ye have
no life in you." Verse 60 and read it.
Verse 60. Many of many therefore of his
disciples when they had heard this said,
"This isn't hard saying,"Who can hear
it?" When Jesus knew in himself, oh,
go ahead, finish that verse and skip
down to verse 63. Okay. When Jesus knew
in himself that his disciples murmured
at it, he said unto them, "Doeth this
offend you?" Verse 63 says, "It is the
spirit that quickenth. The flesh
profitth nothing. The words that I speak
unto you, they are spirit and they are
life.
So he's talking about his word. Skip
down to verse six 6-6 and continue.
From that time many of his disciples
went back and walked no more with him.
Then said Jesus unto the twel, "Will ye
also go away?" Then Simon Peter answered
him, "Lord, to whom shall we go?
Thou has the words of eternal life.
So in the Garden of Eden, you had two
trees that didn't grow out of the
ground. Tree of the knowledge of good
and evil and the tree of life. Tree of
the knowledge of good and evil was
Satan, the devil. And the tree of life
was Jesus before he became Jesus in the
flesh.
So Jesus if they had listened to Jesus
eaten his
word then like I said in in in the 63rd
chap in the 63rd verse here is the words
that I speak they are spirit and they
are life. So when the woman talked to
Satan she wasn't getting wisdom she was
getting knowledge that the Lord wasn't
prepared to give it to him at that time.
But it was the words of the devil
instead of words of God. That's all I
have to say. And that's why he asked uh
why the Lord asked Adam, "Who told you
that you was naked?"
That is correct. Who told you?
All right, Sister Deborah. How about a
time check? Hope that answers your
question. Yes, the time is nine. Do you
want to uh answer one more or this? One
more question and that'll be the last
one for the evening. All right. Uh Alex
says in Galatians 5, the Apostle Paul
says physical circumcision profits
nothing. So why do you teach people must
be circumcised?
Because Paul is not greater than
God. Let's go and see who gave the
circumcision. Or is that Genesis uh uh
is that 17 or 14?
Genesis 17.
Genesis 17. Okay.
See, I think sometime people get mixed
up. They forget that uh uh uh all is the
created. He is not the
creator. Let's see. We're going to start
this at 17 and one. Then we're going to
skip some. Okay. Okay. Okay, sir.
Genesis 17 and verse one. We're going
to start there.
Okay. B uh Genesis 17:1 says, "And when
Abram was 90 years old and nine, the
Lord appeared to Abram and said unto
him, I am the Almighty God. Walk before
me and be thou perfect."
Now, he told and and uh skip down to
verse seven and go ahead.
And I will establish my covenant between
me and thee, and thy seed after thee in
their generations, for an everlasting
covenant, to be a God unto thee, and to
thy seed after thee.
And I will give unto thee, and to thy
seed after thee, the land wherein thou
art a stranger, all the land of Canaan,
for an everlasting possession, and I
will be their God.
And God and God said unto Abraham, "Thou
shalt keep my covenant, therefore, thou
and thy seed after thee in their
generations."
And what is this covenant? Go ahead.
This is the covenant which ye shall keep
between me and you, and thy seed after
thee, every man shall up. Let me let me
make a point here. You notice God's
doing all the talking here? Yes, sir.
Yes, sir. You know, Abraham didn't ask
him for this. He volunteered this. Yes.
Go ahead. Now, every manchild among you
shall be circumcised.
Huh? And ye shall circumcise the flesh
of your foreskin, and it shall be a
token of the covenant betw twix me and
you.
Uh-huh. And he that is 8 days old shall
be circumcised among you. Every manchild
in his generations, he that is born in
the house or bought with money of any
stranger which is not of thy
seed. He that is he that is born in
thine house and he that is bought with
thy money must needs be
circumcised. And my strong word, right?
Mhm. Yes sir.
God said must needs be circumcised. Then
that mean he needs to be circumcised.
Any more than that? Read a little more.
And my covenant shall be in your flesh
for an everlasting covenant.
Uhhuh. And the uncircumcised Oh, sorry.
Go ahead. And the uncircumcised manchild
whose flesh of his foreskin is not
circumcised, that soul shall be cut off
from his people. He hath broken my
covenant.
Now, is God lying here?
No. Impossible. Sir,
now let's go into Exodus the 12th
chapter.
These people make statements don't
understand and they don't understand
that they are telling God you don't know
what you talking
about. Exodus chapter 12 and we going to
look at the uh uh uh the orders of the
Passover. Let's round around 30. Let me
see. Is this 38 or 48? Let me see. 43.
43. Okay. Start reading it there.
Exodus 12:43 says, "And the Lord said
unto Moses and Aaron, this is the
ordinance of the Passover. There shall
no strangers eat
thereof. But every man's servant that is
bought for money, when thou had
circumcised him, then shall he eat
thereof.
Uh-huh. A foreign Oh,
skip down to verse what's that now? 40
8.
Okay, go ahead. And when a stranger
shall sjjoin with thee, and will keep
the Passover to the Lord, let all his
males be circumcised, and then let him
come near and keep it, and he shall be
as one that is born in the land, for no
uncircumcised person shall eat thereof.
Finish it.
One law shall be to him that is homeborn
and unto the stranger that adjoinneth
among you. Thus, Okay. So, you can't you
can't take the Passover, right? Correct.
Right. Who is the Let's go to First
Corinthians 5 and 7. We going to use
Paul's writing.
There you go.
Read it. It says, "Purge out therefore
the old leavenven, that ye may be a new
lump, as ye are unleavenvened, for even
Christ our Passover, is sacrificed for
us."
Wait a minute. He's the Passover. Yes,
sir. You can't even take part in Jesus
if you ain't
circumcised. Yeah.
But now, let's go to Ezekiel the 43rd
chapter.
Yes, sir.
Did the Lord tell you out of the mouth
of two or more witnesses is a fact
established, right? Yes, sir.
Okay. Then we done deal with the Lord.
We didn't deal with Moses and now we're
going to deal with the and uh we didn't
deal with Paul's own writing and now
we're going to deal with Ezekiel the
43rd chapter. Read at verse one. Let you
know that the Lord is back on earth now.
Ezekiel 43 and verse start in verse
Okay. It says, "Afterward, he brought me
to the gate, even the gate that lookth
towards the east east, and behold, the
glory of God of the God of Israel came
from the way of the east, and his voice
was like a noise of many waters, and the
earth shined with his glory."
Now, that mean he was on earth. Go ahead
and read a little bit. And it was
according to the appearance of the
vision which I saw, even according to
the vision that I saw when I came to
destroy the city. And the visions were
like the vision that I saw by the river
Chibbar. And I fell upon my face.
And the glory the glory of the Lord came
into the house by the way of the gate
whose prospect is towards the east. That
house is the temple that's going to be
built for him to come to. And what did
he say there? do it. So the spirit took
me up and brought me into the inner
court, and behold, the glory of the Lord
filled the house. And I heard him
speaking unto me out of the house, and
the man stood by me. And he said unto
me, son of man, the place of my throne
and the place of the souls of my feet,
while I will where where I will dwell in
the midst of the children of Israel
forever, and my holy name shall the
house of Israel no more defile, neither
they nor their kings by their whoredom,
nor by the carcasses of their kings in
their high places.
Now, so that he's telling you here then
that he's back on the earth. He said,
"Son of man, the place of my throne and
the place of the souls of my feet where
I would dwell in the midst of the
children of Israel forever." That mean
he's back on earth, right? Yes. He
didn't return, right?
Now, let's go to Ezekiel 44th chapter
starting in verse one. Okay.
Then he brought me back to the way of
the gate of the outward sanctuary, which
looked towards the east, and it was
shut. Uhhuh. Then said, then said the
Lord unto me, "This gate shall be shut.
It shall not be opened, and no man shall
enter in by it, because the Lord thy God
of Israel hath entered in by it,
therefore it shall be shut."
This is the time when the Lord's return
and this is the time of the thousand
years that he going to rule this earth.
But keep reading. I want you to see what
he said here. Go ahead. It is for the
prince. The prince he shall sit in it to
eat bread before the Lord. He shall
enter by the way of the porch of that
gate and shall go out by the way of the
same.
then brought he me the way of the north
gate before the house. And let's go down
to verse six now and continue verse six.
And thou shalt say to the rebellious
even to the house of Israel, thus sayeth
the Lord God, oh ye house of Israel, let
it suffice you of all your abominations.
And what is that? Go ahead. and that ye
have brought into my sanctuary
strangers, uncircumcised in heart, and
uncircumcised in flesh, to be in my
sanctuary to pollute it, even my house,
when ye offer my bread, the fat, and the
blood. And they have broken my covenant
because of all your abominations.
Wait a minute. Israel did that, didn't
it? Yep. Yes.
Israel is the one that caused them to
break God's covenant. And he's telling
the stranger, see, and the people that
try to kick against circumcision, they
don't understand that this was only uh
Paul had issue with that for the
Gentiles. It never was an issue with
Israel. That's why he said a stranger.
He keeps saying a stranger. He said,
"And uh it said and and what it said, do
we read a new uncircumcised stranger?"
Read that again. That no that's that's
down in verse n or that's in seven and
going dropping down to nine. But in
verse seven it says and that ye have
brought into my sanctuary strangers
uncircumcised in heart and uncircumcised
in flesh to be in my sanctuary to
pollute it even my house when ye offered
my bread the fat and the blood. And they
have broken my covenant because of all
your abominations.
And this is Israel. Paul Paul was an
Israelite. Mhm. And so what did he say
about this stranger? Skip down and read
verse N. Thus sayeth the Lord God, no
stranger uncircumcised in heart, nor
uncircumcised in flesh, shall enter into
my sanctuary of any stranger that is
among the children of
Israel. So now, if you ain't going to
enter into the sanctuary, you got a
problem, don't you? No.
This is
Ezekiel. So now you read Galatians, but
I'm going to read something to you too.
Let's go into
Acts 16th chapter and read verse one.
Acts 16:1
says, "Then came he to Derby and Listra,
and behold, a certain disciple was there
named Timothas, the son of a certain
woman, which was a Jewish and believed,
but his father was a Greek." Go ahead.
Which was well reported of by the
brethren that was at Lististra and
Iconium.
He would have he would have Paul he
would Paul have to go forth with him and
took and circumcised him because of the
Jews which were in those quarters for
they knew all that his father was a
Greek. Wait a minute. Why did Paul
circumcise Timothy at the circumcision
didn't avail anything? That's right.
Paul is the one that did a circumcise
there. Know why? is because he had a
Hebrew mother. Oh, and and all the
argument was about
circumcising this gentile which was a
stranger. And which God said when he
gave Abraham, not the
Jews, when he gave Abraham the
circumcision, he told him then all of
the ones and male going to be
circumcised and the one that's bought
with money represent that you that money
represent the blood of Jesus.
So now if you going to do that
then you going to have to be circumcised
because God made Abraham. We're going to
go one more scripture and we going to
leave us alone. Let's go into Galatians
the third chapter now. Back to the third
chapter. Okay.
Because the people that argued about the
circumcision more than anybody else's
are Israelites and there was never it
never was an issue about Israelites
being
circumcised. Never. But then if you
going to take part of
a a a Passover and Jesus is the
Passover, then let's show you what the
Lord said. Let's start reading this uh
uh at uh
uh Galatians
3 and start reading at verse 26.
Okay, it says, "For ye are all the
children of God by faith in Christ
Jesus. For as many of you as have been
baptized into Christ have put on
Christ." Uhhuh. There is neither Jew nor
Greek. There is neither bond nor free.
There is neither male nor female. For ye
are all one in Christ Jesus. And if ye
be and if ye be Christ, then are ye
Abraham's seed and hes according to the
promise? So what did the Lord tell
Abraham to do with his seed? You must be
circumcised. Be circumcised. That's
right. Change clothes. Good night.
All right. Good night. Yes, sir. Good
night.
All right. We know that we have went
over, but we wanted to make sure that
the true gospel of Jesus got spread even
on that very last question. So, we like
to thank everybody who tuned in with us
this evening. We thank you and we say
that if you submitted a question and we
didn't get to it, please don't resubmit
it. Deborah, take it and put it into
rotation.
So until we all come together again, be
safe, be blessed, stay prayed up, and
may the Lord have mercy on us all. As
brother James closes us out,
our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name, thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread. And forgive us our debts as we
forgive our debtors. And lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom and the
power and the glory forever. In Jesus
name we